## **PAUL ENWEREM**

<u>paulthechampion28@gmail.com</u> <u>www.paulthechampion.com</u> <u>www.linkedin.com/in/paul-enwerem-9a307518b/</u> Toronto, Canada (416) 896-3327

## **Objective**

An ambitious, young, and hardworking Software developer with over 5+ years of professional experience in MongoDB, Express JS, React JS, Redux JS, Node JS (M, E, R, R, N) and many more, seeking full-time employment as a mid-senior level Software developer.

## **Skills**

#### PROGRAMMING AND DEVELOPMENT LANGUAGES, TOOLS, SKILLS, AND SOFTWARE

Html 5 and CSS 3

♣ Node JS

Express JS

🖶 REST API

Typescript

↓ Unit Test (JEST)

JavaScript and JQuery

React JS and Next JS

Redux

**┿** C#

♣ GitHub

Bitbucket

♣ SQL

👃 MongoDB

Vue JS

**♣** GIT

♣ Amazon Web Service (AWS)

♣ Bug Fixing and Problem Solving

## **Experiences**

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER S&P GLOBAL LONDON, ONTARIO

#### **OCTOBER 2021 – DATE**

- Working with one of the biggest financial service companies in the NYSE
- Writing code in Vue JS, Node JS, ASP.NET and C# with a Jest unit test coverage of 90%+
- Worked with WCAG 2.0 standards to make the clients web application more accessible to people with disabilities.
- Building new features like Stock, ETF and MF Charts, Funds Compare tools, calendars, calculators etc.
- ₩ Worked with a team of 15 and properly utilized the Agile framework.
- Regular production support to investigate and fix Live bugs on the clients' production environment.

# FULLSTACK DEVELOPER DAVITO IMMIGRATION SERVICE BRAMPTON, ONTARIO MAY 2020 – OCTOBER 2021

Despite the hardships of the pandemic and there being a shortage of opportunity, I was able to persevere and land an opportunity in a new country. Davito Immigration service is an immigration company based in Brampton, Ontario. My team was tasked with creating and deploying their online web application. I completed this task by using the following:

- ♣ Node JS and Express to handle the backend and Api Creation
- React JS to handle the front end.
- Followed the Figma design patterns to ensure my code is in line with the Company's requirements.
- Css and JavaScript for styling
- ♣ Git for Version control, Heroku and Go daddy for deployment, using DNS target to combine both.
- Registering for SSL certificate to keep the site safe and secure.

## FULLSTACK DEVELOPER NADA CREATE

#### REMOTE

#### **NOVEMBER 2019 – MAY 2020**

- Wrote well-designed, testable, efficient code using Node JS, React JS, Express for the company's e-commerce web application.
- Application of Passport JS to create and authenticate Users for the e-commerce application.
- Worked with Paystack API to integrate payments for each product.
- ♣ Meticulously adhered to the Figma UI/UX design to ensure compliance with client's requirements.
- ♣ Always delivered my code on time and completed all the companies Acceptance criteria always.

#### WEB DEVELOPER

KEER NG

LAGOS, NIGERIA

#### **DECEMBER 2018 - MARCH 2019**

- ♣ Developed and designed the front-end of a web application to showcase products and services for Keer NG
- → Delivered responsive, cross-browser compatible and accessible website.
- Wrote code mainly in HTML, CSS, and vanilla JavaScript.
- ♣ Produced stunning visual elements of web applications by translation UI/UX design wireframes into code
- ₩ Worked directly with client to develop technical solutions for business cases.

## **Education**

## BABCOCK UNIVERSITY, OGUN STATE, NIGERIA B.SC INTERNATIONAL LAW AND DIPLOMACY

- 2015 2019
  - Active member of the Babcock University Computer Club (B.U.C.C).
  - Honors degree (3.75 G.P.A.)
  - Led a class of over 150 students as an Assistant Class Representative.

#### NEW HORIZON CODING BOOT CAMP, OGUN STATE, NIGERIA APRIL 2018- AUGUST 2018

♣ Primary Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#.

## CALEB INTERNATIONAL SECONDARY SCHOOL LAGOS, NIGERIA

2009-2015